[orchestral music playing]
[machine guns firing]
[Chrollo]
Forever set, a precious moon is lost.
The others mourn him with ceremony grand.
Rising up to heaven, the mighty moon
of frost...
with a melody from the mourning band.
[theme music playing]
ASSAULT x AND x IMPACT
-[brakes screeching]
-[passengers groaning]
[announcer] Attention, passengers.
We will be making an emergency stop.
-Please watch your step.
-Wait, did something happen?
Dunno.
[phone ringing]
Are they here?
Yeah, it's got to be them!
They're the only ones I can think of
who are powerful enough
to take on a whole crowd on their own!
[cries in pain]
-[gasps] Hey. Hey!
-[crashing]
Listen! Figure out how many enemies
we're up against!
Do whatever it takes to stop them!
Don't let them
anywhere near this building!
[grumbling] They're late!
Our escorts aren't here?
Their names are Melody and Basho.
Unfortunately, sir, all the traffic
in Yorknew City
has come to a grinding halt.
They're probably stuck.
[Nostrade] [grumbling]
It's dangerous for Neon to be here.
Isn't there any way to get her out?
[guard] The ambulance we requested
is already on its way.
It shouldn't be much longer, sir.
[Nostrade]
Ambulance? Oh, yes, that's right.
[Kurapika] Something's wrong here.
The man entered the building with Neon
and then called for a doctor...
Wait, sir?
Kurapika, do not leave my daughter's side
until the ambulance arrives. Understand?
But sir, my assignment
is to kill the Phantom Troupe--
That was when I thought
Neon would be home already.
Instead, she's here and unconscious,
completely exposed to the Troupe.
I must ensure her safety.
I want you here for the time being.
Please, Kurapika.
I understand.
[assassin snickering]
It's such a pity, isn't it?
They aren't putting up much of a fight.
Well, I guess it was stupid to expect--
[grunts]
[sirens wailing]
Damn it! They're crazier than I thought.
They're trying to launch
a full-frontal attack
with only ten people.
[doctor] My goodness.
When the hell did this place turn
into such a damn warzone, huh?
So, where is the patient?
[EMTs gasping]
[Bean] I don’t have any reason to believe
that you aren’t a member
of the Phantom Troupe.
Make just one funny move
and I'll blow your head off.
Follow me.
I will need to inspect all of you.
What's that?
Damn you.
-[indistinct chatter]
-[man] Give me a break!
[announcer]
All trains have been stopped at this time.
The safety of our customers
is of utmost importance to us.
So we ask that you continue
to wait patiently for now
[Gon]
I'm not getting any reception down here.
And we don't know when the trains
will start moving again.
Then I guess we'll just have to run.
[sighs]
Weren't you hired here as an assassin?
Why don't you quit hiding out
in this room and go fight?
Unless you got too scared
when the Phantom Troupe showed up?
Well, actually, I requested
that Kurapika stay here.
I understand that he's been hired
by the Ten Dons,
but I'm a bit worried about my daughter.
It's fine. I won't sell you out.
But still, I know you're being paid well,
so I expect you to do your job.
[chuckles]
He's right,
I really should do something to help out.
I could patrol the building
at the very least.
I suppose so.
But you must come back immediately
if I call on you.
My daughter's safety takes precedence.
[Kurapika] Yes, sir.
[man 1]
How long do we have to wait?
[man 2]
Hey, what's going on outside?
[man 3]
Yeah, I hear explosions nearby!
When is the auction gonna start?
What the hell is going on here, anyway?
[stammering]
Please, sir, it shouldn't be much longer.
Is the auction still on or isn't it?
[Kurapika] Everyone here is either
a leader or an executive member.
They're endangering themselves needlessly
only to prove they aren't afraid
of the Troupe.
Give me back my phone!
I don't know what's happening out there.
I need my weapons back, too!
[auctioneer stammering]
As you know, sir, the rule state
that weapons are banned
during the auction.
[man] What happens if they get inside?
We fight them with our bare hands?
[Kurapika]
It's starting to get chaotic in here.
If they're not careful,
the auction organizers will lose control
of the situation before much longer.
[phone vibrating]
Yes. Hello?
-[Gon] Hey! Kurapika?
-[gasps]
[Gon]
Oh, good! We finally got a hold of you.
-[Kurapika] Gon?
-Yeah, can you talk right now?
Uh, I'm a little busy.
So I'll have to call you back.
[Gon] Wait! Just give me a minute!
I have something I really need
to tell you.
Killua and I found the Troupe.
-[gasps]
-[Gon] Actually, they kind of caught us.
[Kurapika]
What in the hell were you thinking?
Do you have any idea
how dangerous they are?
I thought I knew until we met them.
They're really tough.
As it stands, we don't have a chance
against them.
That's why we need your help.
And we want to help you, too.
[Kurapika] This isn't a game.
I'm not going to help you
get yourselves killed.
We found their base.
Wanna know where it is?
[Kurapika] I have my own sources.
We learned some of their abilities.
Don't you wanna know about them?
[Kurapika] That's enough!
Just stay away from the Phantom Troupe!
[Killua] You're the "chain user"
who killed one of them, right?
You do realize that they're dead set
on finding you?
But if you won't even consider thinking
of me and Gon as your friends and equals,
we'll do whatever the hell it takes
to make you help us. [grumbles]
[Gon] Kurapika...
One of the Phantom Troupe guys...
he started crying right in front of us.
He said that he could never forgive
whoever killed his friend.
And then when I saw him do that,
it made me really angry.
I couldn't forgive them.
Look, we want to stop them too!
So, please, Kurapika.
[Kurapika] I'll... call you back later.
[Killua] But if you won't even consider
thinking of me and Gon
as your friends and equals...
[Gon] Look! We want to stop them too!
[crowd gasping]
-[Mafioso 1] Here they come!
-[Mafioso 2] Don't let them escape!
-[Mafioso 3] I can feel the heat!
-[Mafioso 4] Someone's coming!
-[Mafioso 5] Does he have a gun?
-[Mafioso 6] Who's stationed here?
[man] Go! Go back! It's no use.
The Troupe is too powerful!
I'm serious. We don't stand
a chance against them.
Do you wanna see how strong they are?
'Cause I can show you!
They're this strong! [laughs maniacally]
Damn it!
[laughter stops]
[Shalnark] Aww, he broke.
I need to find my next puppet.
[Mafioso] Are you okay? I found the corpse
of one of the assassins!
[gasps]
Someone has already gotten
inside the building!
[Kurapika] Damn.
-[man 1] Who are these guys?
-[man 2] It's hopeless!
Come on! Get back here and fight!
[sighs] What's going on?
It's me. Where the hell is our backup?
What are you doing?
[Mafioso] They should be there any minute.
And we'll be arriving shortly--
[grunting in pain]
[Bean] Is this really happening?
The 2,000 armed men
that were supposed to assemble here...
Are they all getting killed?
Now what?
There are Troupe members
inside the building already.
It's me, Bean!
Get the Ten Dons on the line.
And hurry!
[Kurapika] The intruder must be
a member of the Troupe.
They're trying to steal the rest
of the merchandise
and avenge their comrade.
He said he could never forgive
whoever killed his friend.
[Kurapika] That's what I'm hoping for!
[glass smashing]
[man] Hey! Enough already!
Give us the weapons we handed over!
And do it now!
[auctioneer]
But, sir, the rules state that--
To hell with the damn rules,
hear me?
You know what's happening, don't you?
I'm not stupid.
You've got professional assassins here.
I've been seeing them all over the place.
If you're gonna depend on those freaks,
then you might as well let us fight!
For those of you who don't know,
my name is Zeno Zoldyck.
Zoldyck? Like the famous family
of assassins?
Did the Ten Dons actually call in
these monsters?
At the moment,
one bandit has infiltrated this building.
[crowd gasping]
He has already killed a number
of the assassins
that were hired by your people.
It wouldn't much matter if each of you
was armed to the teeth.
I could still eliminate the lot of you
in under seven seconds.
The enemy is every bit as capable.
[crowd gasping]
If you understand,
then just shut up and wait.
Disregard if you would rather die.
Well, then?
[Silva] A single strike from behind.
Impressive.
His bloodlust was only exposed
for a brief instant,
and barely a trace remains.
[sighs]
I suppose I'll have to use En.
although it really is
such an exhausting technique.
Let's start from the roof
and then make our way down.
[Silva]
This building's radius is 100 meters.
Think you can handle it, Dad?
You fool. I could do 300 meters, easily.
[cracks knuckles]
One thing is certain.
We're not getting paid enough for this.
[phone vibrating]
Kurapika, you're late!
Hurry back at once
and stay by Neon's side!
Yes, sir. I'm on my way.
Damn it!
[Chrollo] We meet again.
[Silva] You remember me?
[Chrollo] How could I forget?
You did kill one of my people.
[Silva] It wasn't easy.
Now, Dad, be careful.
He can steal people's abilities.
[gasps]
[Silva] Huh?
[panting]
[Chrollo] Two on one sure is rough.
[Silva] Hmm. Must be a good knife
if it can scratch my skin.
A mid-era Ben's knife by the looks of it.
Hmm. The shape must mean it's poisoned.
You all right?
Not a problem.
[Chrollo] Not a problem?
Point one milligrams of that stuff
is more than enough to paralyze a whale.
[Zeno]
So you can steal other people's Nen?
Then you're a Specialist.
You might even be a threat if you could
use those stolen powers freely.
However, that implies
a higher activation cost.
You couldn't have gotten
the ability, otherwise.
If I had to make a guess,
you must clear four or five conditions
before stealing an ability.
[Chrollo] He's right.
The old man's a tough customer.
Trying to meet those conditions
while fighting both of us
will be difficult indeed,
meaning that you won't be able
to steal our abilities as long
as we keep you engaged in battle.
That poisoned knife of yours is proof.
[Chrollo] Right again.
Guess I have no choice.
-Watch my back, Silva.
-Hmm?
As soon as I have him pinned down,
even if you have to kill me,
end him.
Got it.
[Chrollo] He focused his aura
into his hand.
The energy potential will be huge.
I don't have the defenses to block it.
-[Zeno] Huh.
-[Silva] Hmm.
SKILL HUNTER: BANDIT'S SECRET
[Zeno] A conjured cloak, eh?
Hmm. This could be trouble.
Even if it's a stolen ability,
it would be reckless to attack
without knowing what it does.
Or so the average person would think.
But...
DRAGON HEAD: LONG-TOU XI-HUA
DRAGON LANCE
[snickers and yells]
[Zeno] I see what he's doing.
He can trap the abilities of others
in the conjured book,
take them out and use them
any time he pleases.
But there's a catch.
He can't use those abilities
unless he holds the book open
the entire time.
The cloak is also a conjured item.
It doesn't look like he's planning
to attack,
but it's obvious that he's attempting
to close the distance between us.
So, it must be a defensive tool
that can be utilized
to draw closer to an enemy,
and counter-attack.
We can lower the risk
if we keep our distance.
We'll wait for our chance,
then strike!
[Chrollo]
This old man is really something.
He managed to read my mind in an instant.
Doubt I'd capture him alive.
[Silva] So the ability disappears
whenever he closes the book.
In any case, he's impressive.
He's dodging Dad's attacks by a hair,
all while keeping an eye on me.
His attacks have improved since last time.
So we don't have any clue
what he's capable of.
If we were to stop him,
we may just have to pay with our lives.
[Chrollo] Huh?
Silva! Do it now!
[laughs]
[Silva grunts]
[narrator] A thunderous tremor ripped
through Yorknew City.
Kurapika had no idea that those shockwaves
would lead to an unexpected development.
[theme music playing]
-[Gon] Coming up, Gon...
-[Killua] And Killua's...
[both] Hunterpedia!
-I'm Gon!
-I'm Killua!
[both] And this is our Hunterpedia!
Today, we're introducing Shalnark,
a member of the Troupe
who's really smart, knowledgeable
and cunning!
He can put a Nen antenna
right on his targets,
and control them by phone!
[both] Black voice!
[Gon] Next time:
"Fake and Psyche."
-[Gon] Kopitor?
-[Killua] Kotorpi?
[Gon] Kortopi!